Bodman Family Papers, 1687-1980
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- GENERATION VI
  - Edward Cushman (1840-1917) and Ida (Berdan) (1855-1937) Bodman
    - Edward
      - Correspondence - General
        - Sheridan Lumber Co., 1893 (Box 15, Folder 373)
        - Francis Louis Slade, 1904-10 (Box 15, Folder 374)
        - W.S. Smallidge, 1902-11 (Box 15, Folder 375)
        - Smith and Baker, 1896-1902 (Box 15, Folder 376)
        - State National Bank, 1893-1905 (Box 15, Folder 377)
        - Steinberger, Sinn & Co., 1911-13 (Box 15, Folder 378)
        - T, 1886-1913 (Box 15, Folder 379)
        - U-V, 1886-1912 (Box 15, Folder 380)
        - United Boxboard/United Paperboard, 1907-13 (Box 15, Folder 381)
        - W-Z, 1886-1913 (Box 15, Folder 382-383)
        - H.S. Wallbridge & Co., 1886-93 (Box 15, Folder 384)
        - Ward, Hayden & Satterlee, 1902-04 (Box 15, Folder 385)
        - Chas. T. Wing, 1888 (Box 15, Folder 386)
        - WCTU Settlement School, 1912-13, undated (Box 15, Folder 387)
        - Morrison Waite Young, 1899-1912 (Box 15, Folder 388)
        - Outgoing [2 bound volumes], 1895-99 (Box 16)
        - Outgoing [miscellaneous items], 1888-1911 (Box 16, Folder 389)
      - Diary, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 390)
      - Financial
        - Journal, 1869-79 (Box 16)
        - Ledger, 1869-79 (Box 16)
        - Journal, 1880-89 (Box 17)
        - Ledger, 1880-89 (Box 17)
        - Journal, 1890-1902 (Box 17)
        - Ledger, 1890-1902 (Box 18)
        - Journal, 1903-14 (Box 18)
        - Ledger, 1903-14 (Box 18)
        - Journal, 1915-20 (Box 19)
        - Ledger, 1915-19 (Box 19)
      - Memberships, subscriptions, 1886-1915 (Box 19, Folder 391)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1888-1915, undated (Box 19, Folder 392)
      - Will, estate inventory, 1915, undated (Box 19, Folder 393)
    - Ida
      - Correspondence
        - A-Be, 1886-1923, undated (Box 19, Folder 394)
        - Bo-H, 1886-1901, undated (Box 19, Folder 395)
        - K-Z, 1877-1927, undated (Box 19, Folder 396)
        - Clara Philena Bodman, undated (Box 19, Folder 397)
        - George Milmine Bodman, undated (Box 19, Folder 398)
        - Herbert Luther Bodman, 1896-1923 (Box 19, Folder 399)
        - To Millie Berdan(?), 1864 (Box 19, Folder 400)
      - Financial
        - Ledgers, 1888-1919 (Box 20)
        - Journal, 1897-1915 (Box 20)
        - Ledger, 1897-1915 (Box 20)
        - Journal, 1916-23 (Box 21)
        - Ledger, 1916-22 (Box 21)
        - IMB Trust ledger, 1930-47 (Box 21)
        - Ledger sheets, 1923 (Box 21, Folder 401)
      - Genealogy
        - Berdan family
          - Charts, undated (Box 22, Folder 402)
          - Correspondence, 1923-46, undated (Box 22, Folder 403)
          - Notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 404)
          - Research material, 1839-1935, undated (Box 22, Folder 405)
        - Bodman family, 1917-38, undated (Box 22, Folder 406)
        - Kip family, undated (Box 22, Folder 407)
        - Selden family
          - Charts, undated (Box 22, Folder 408)
          - Correspondence, 1908-37, undated (Box 22, Folder 409)
          - Notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 410)
          - Research material, 1877, undated (Box 22, Folder 411)
        - Waite family, 1864-1944, undated (Box 22, Folder 412)
        - Williams family, 1925, undated (Box 22, Folder 413)
        - Society of the Colonial of Dames of New York: claim forms, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 414)
        - Miscellaneous charts, undated (Box 22, Folder 415)
        - Miscellaneous notes and research material, 1931, undated (Box 22, Folder 416)
      - Memorabilia, 1872-94, undated (Box 22, Folder 417)
      - Miscellaneous papers re household, 1919-27, undated (Box 22, Folder 418)
      - Scrapbook, 1868-1917 (Box 22)
  - Lewis Henry Bodman (1840-1909): miscellaneous papers, 1872, 1887 (Box 23, Folder 419)
  - (Luther) Whitney (1845-1917) and Grace (Smith) (1850-1934) Bodman
    - (Luther) Whitney (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, 1858, 1879, 1886 (Box 23, Folder 420)
    - Record of the Self Control Club, 1857-62 (Box 23, Folder 421)
    - Grace: Bible, 1885 (Box 23, Folder 422)
  - Martha (Lyman) Bodman (1840-1937): letter to parents, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 423)
  - Mary Sylvia (1847-1928) and Minnie Elizabeth (1857-1926) Bodman: correspondence, 1867?-75 (Box 23, Folder 424)
- GENERATION VII
  - George Milmine Bodman (1882-1950)
    - Correspondence
      - Herbert Luther Bodman, Sr., 1899-1900, 1918-19 (Box 23, Folder 425)
      - Re genealogy, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 426)
  - George Milmine and Herbert Luther Bodman, Sr.: trust account ledger, 1932-36 (Box 23, Folder 427)
  - Henry Edward (1874-1963) and Florence (Taylor) Bodman (1872-1960)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1897-1963 (Box 23, Folder 428)
    - Henry
      - Correspondence from Lewis Henry Bodman, 1900 (Box 23, Folder 429)
      - Genealogy
        - Correspondence, 1940-60 (Box 23, Folder 430)
        - Notes and research material, undated (Box 23, Folder 431)
      - Grand Jury Investigation into Banking Conditions in Wayne County, Michigan
        - Journal, Feb-Mar 1933 (Box 23, Folder 432)
        - Miscellaneous papers, Feb-Jun 1933 (Box 23, Folder 433)
        - Testimony, Jun 21-22, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 434)
      - Speeches, 1932, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 435)
      - Writings, c. 1928-1958 (?) (Box 24, Folder 436)
  - Herbert Luther, Sr. (1880-1958) and Theodora (Dunham) (1895-1983) Bodman
    - Correspondence
      - Carlyle Berdan Bodman, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 437)
      - Ellen-Fairbanks (Diggs) Bodman, 1954-56 (Box 24, Folder 438)
      - Herbert Luther Bodman, Jr., 1944-45, undated (Box 24, Folder 439)
      - Violet Bodman, 1926?-40, undated (Box 24, Folder 440)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1938, 1943, undated (Box 24, Folder 441)
    - Wedding
      - Memento of service, 1917 (Box 24, Folder 442)
      - Announcements and invitations, 1917 (Box 24, Folder 443)
      - Announcement list, 1917 (Box 24, Folder 444)
      - Guest list, 1917 (Box 24, Folder 445)
    - Herbert
      - Biographical material and memorabilia
        - Miscellaneous, 1883-1958, undated (Box 24, Folder 446)
        - Obituaries, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 447)
        - Scrapbook, 1903-13 (Box 24, Folder 448)
        - War Service - World War I
          - Field notebooks, 1918, undated (Box 24, Folder 449)
          - Passes, notes, receipts, miscellaneous, 1919,undated (Box 24, Folder 450)
          - Enrollments, certificates, citations, 1916-19 (Box 24, Folder 451)
          - Correspondence, 1916-19 (Box 24, Folder 452)
          - Orders, 1917-19, undated (Box 24, Folder 453)
        - War Service - World War II: miscellaneous papers, 1942-45, undated (Box 24, Folder 454)
      - Correspondence - Family
        - Edward Cushman Bodman, 1901, 1907? (Box 25, Folder 455)
        - Edward Dunham Bodman, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 456)
        - George Milmine Bodman, 1937, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 457)
        - Herbert Luther Bodman, Jr., 1943-45 (Box 25, Folder 458)
        - Theodora (Dunham) Bodman, 1917, 1930, undated (Box 25, Folder 459-460)
        - Violet Bodman, 1938, 1940, undated (Box 25, Folder 461)
        - Miscellaneous Bodmans, 1907?, 1931, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 462)
        - To "Uncle John," 1900 (Box 25, Folder 463)
      - Correspondence - Business, 1901-11, 1937-42, undated (Box 25, Folder 464-468)
      - Correspondence - General, 1906-47, undated (Box 25, Folder 469-472)
      - Diaries, 1905-7 Feb 1908 (Box 25, Folder 473)
      - Diaries, 8 Feb 1908-1912 (Box 26)
      - Diaries of cruises (ship's logs), 1902-16, 1948-49 (Box 26)
      - Financial
        - Milmine, Bodman and Co.: petty cash book, 1908-35 (Box 27)
        - HLB Trust account book, 1927-37 (Box 27)
        - HLB Trust for Children, account book, 1934-38 (Box 27)
        - Balance sheets, 1909-12 (Box 27, Folder 474)
      - Speeches, 1935, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 475)
      - Writings
        - Prose pieces, 1915, 1933-35, undated (Box 27, Folder 476)
        - Poetry, undated (Box 27, Folder 477)
        - Notes for a biographical sketch (?) of Ida Maria (Berdan) Bodman, c. 1935 (Box 27, Folder 478)
    - Theodora
      - Biographical material and memorabilia
        - Cookbook, 1913 (Box 28, Folder 479)
        - Education
          - Class notes - Latin, 1910 (Box 28, Folder 480)
          - Class notes - Literature, 1911, 1916, undated (Box 28, Folder 481)
          - St. Timothy's School: yearbook and writings for school literary magazine, 1911-12 (Box 28, Folder 482)
        - Miscellaneous, 1914-76, undated (Box 28, Folder 483)
        - Scrapbooks, 1930, 1973-82 (Box 28, Folder 484)
        - World War I
          - Miscellaneous, 1916-18, undated (Box 28, Folder 485)
          - Passports, passes, visas, 1916-18, undated (Box 28, Folder 486)
      - Correspondence - Family
        - Edward Dunham Bodman, 1926?-36 (Box 28, Folder 487)
        - Herbert Luther Bodman, Jr., 1943-45, undated (Box 28, Folder 488-493)
        - Herbert Luther Bodman, Sr., 1916-44, undated (Box 29, Folder 494-512)
        - Herbert Luther Bodman, Sr., recorded message, undated (Box 29, Folder 513)
        - Ida (Berdan) Bodman, 1917 (Box 29, Folder 514)
        - Violet Bodman, 1926?-40 (Box 29, Folder 515)
        - Dows Dunham, 1917, 1922 (Box 29, Folder 516)
        - Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr., 1914-18, 1926-27 (Box 29, Folder 517)
        - Mary (Dows) Dunham, 1926-27, undated (Box 29, Folder 518)
        - Miscellaneous Dunhams, 1914-34, undated (Box 30, Folder 519)
        - To family from France, 1916-17, undated (Box 30, Folder 520-522)
      - Correspondence - General, 1907-76, undated (Box 30, Folder 523-534)
      - Diaries, 1909, 1912 (Box 30, Folder 535-536)
      - Diaries, 1913-17 (Box 31)
      - Transcript of diary (France), 1916 (Box 31, Folder 537)
      - Diaries, 1929-78 (Box 32)
      - Financial: TDB Trust ledgers, 1936-48 (Box 33)
      - Speeches
        - Texts, 1917-18 (Box 34, Folder 538)
        - Clippings, programs, posters, 1917-18 (Box 34, Folder 539)
      - Writings
        - "Grandma Dows," undated (Box 34, Folder 540)
        - "I Still Remember," undated [published privately, 1986] (Box 34, Folder 541)
        - "Letters of a War Worker," Red Cross Magazine, Vol.XII, No. 7, Aug 1917 (Box 34, Folder 542)
        - "Old Brookville," ms. and research materials, undated (Box 34, Folder 543-544)
        - "The Story of William," undated (Box 34, Folder 545)
        - Miscellaneous, 1905-26, undated (Box 34, Folder 546-548)
- GENERATION VIII
  - Edward Dunham Bodman (1922- )
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1937, undated (Box 34, Folder 549)
    - Correspondence to family from China, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 550)
    - Henry Taylor Bodman (1906-87): correspondence re genealogy, 1972-75 (Box 34, Folder 551)
  - Herbert Luther, Jr. (1924- ) and Ellen-Fairbanks (Diggs) (1924- ) Bodman
    - Correspondence to family from Beirut, 1952-53 (Box 34, Folder 552)
    - Ellen Fairbanks Bodman to Herbert L. Bodman, Jr., 1964 (Box 34, Folder 552a)
    - Genealogy
      - Correspondence with authors of A Bodman Chronicle
        - Outgoing, 1977-80, undated (Box 34, Folder 553)
        - Richard Wainwright Bodman, 1975-80, undated (Box 34, Folder 554-556)
        - Robert Edgar Bodman, 1975-Aug 1979 (Box 34, Folder 557-559)
        - Robert Edgar Bodman, Oct 1979-1981, undated (Box 35, Folder 560)
      - Correspondence - General
        - Helen (Bradley) Bodman, 1973-79, undated (Box 35, Folder 561)
        - Helen (Shepard) Bodman, 1975-76 (Box 35, Folder 562)
        - Henry Taylor Bodman, 1975-78 (Box 35, Folder 563)
        - Samuel Wright Bodman, 1979, undated (Box 35, Folder 564)
        - Mary Emily (Bodman) Kenner, 1976-80, undated (Box 35, Folder 565)
        - Katherine Crosby Meese, 1978-80 (Box 35, Folder 566)
        - Ruth (Leiserson) Sims, 1975, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 567)
        - Louise (Hall) Tharp, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 568)
        - Lewis Turco, 1974-77 (Box 35, Folder 569)
        - Phyllis Winkler, 1974-78 (Box 35, Folder 570)
        - Miscellaneous family, 1975-80, undated (Box 35, Folder 571)
        - Miscellaneous non-family, 1970-79 (Box 35, Folder 572)
      - Notes
        - Charts, undated (Box 35, Folder 573)
        - Bodman biographical notes in published sources - index by Richard Wainwright Bodman, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 574)
        - Bodman houses, undated (Box 35, Folder 575)
        - Bodman papers: miscellaneous lists and indexes, 1977, undated (Box 35, Folder 576)
        - Bodman papers: chronological list of letters, c. 1978 (Box 35, Folder 577)
        - Bodman papers: miscellaneous lists by individual, c. 1978 (Box 35, Folder 578)
        - Martha (Warner) Bodman genealogy, undated (Box 35, Folder 579)
        - Unlocated Bodmans, 1976, undated (Box 35, Folder 580)
        - Miscellaneous, 1939, 1976, undated (Box 35, Folder 581)
      - Poems re family history, 1974-76, undated (Box 35, Folder 582)
      - Publication - A Bodman Chronicle
        - Advertisements, reviews, circular letters, sales report, 1979-80, undated (Box 35, Folder 583)
        - Correspondence re permissions and printing, 1978-79 (Box 35, Folder 584)
        - Distribution list, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 585)
        - Illustrations and layout, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 586)
        - Typescript, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 587-592)
      - Research material
        - Bodman genealogies, 1889, 1914, undated (Box 37, Folder 593)
        - Bodman genealogy by Glenn Taylor Bodman, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 594)
        - Bodman name heraldry, undated (Box 37, Folder 595)
        - Albert Holmes Bodman: typescript of material in Illinois State Historical Library, 1864 (Box 37, Folder 596)
        - Edward Cushman Bodman, 1917, undated (Box 37, Folder 597)
        - Elam Bodman, 1863, 1866 (Box 37, Folder 598)
        - Lewis and Emily (Nash) Bodman, 1877-90 (Box 37, Folder 599)
        - Luther Bodman, Jr., 1862-1938 (Box 37, Folder 600)
        - (Luther) Whitney Bodman, 1917, undated (Box 37, Folder 601)
        - Manoah Bodman, 1814-1973, undated (Box 37, Folder 602)
        - Theophilus Bodman, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 603)
        - Miscellaneous Bodmans, 1850-1980 (Box 37, Folder 604)
        - Great Britain, 1873-1925 (Box 37, Folder 605)
        - Bement, IL, 1875, 1980, undated (Box 37, Folder 606)
        - Hatfield, MA, 1889, 1935 (Box 37, Folder 607)
        - Williamsburg, MA, 1874-1978 (Box 37, Folder 608)
        - Pratt family, undated (Box 37, Folder 609)
        - Sophia Smith genealogy, undated (Box 37, Folder 610)
        - Hadley chests, 1935-80 (Box 37, Folder 611)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1946, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 612)
    - Herbert, Jr.
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1936, 1944, undated (Box 37, Folder 613)
      - Account books, 1924-49 (Box 37, Folder 614-615)
    - Ellen-Fairbanks: miscellaneous papers, 1936, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 616)
  - Robert Edgar Bodman (1913- ): estate of Edgar Sereno Bodman, auction advertisement, c. 1972 (Box 37, Folder 617)
  - Violet Bodman (1920- )
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1920-47, undated (Box 37, Folder 618)
    - Correspondence - general, 1926-44, undated (Box 37, Folder 619)
    - Correspondence from Herbert Luther Bodman, Jr., 1944-45 (Box 37, Folder 620)
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Clara Philena Bodman, undated (Box 38, Folder 621)
  - Edward Cushman and Ida (Berdan) Bodman, 1878, undated (Box 38, Folder 622)
  - Edward Dunham Bodman, Herbert Luther Bodman, Jr., and Violet Bodman, 1923-50, undated (Box 38, Folder 623)
  - Herbert Luther, Sr. and Theodora (Dunham) Bodman
    - Herbert, Sr.
      - Portraits and snapshots, 1891-1918, undated (Box 38, Folder 624)
      - Groups, 1931-56, undated (Box 38, Folder 625)
      - Albums (2), undated (Box 38, Folder 626-627)
      - California, 1898 (Box 38, Folder 628)
      - Washington, 1910 (Box 38, Folder 629)
    - Theodora
      - Portraits and snapshots, 1918, undated (Box 38, Folder 630)
      - Groups, 1972, undated (Box 38, Folder 631)
      - School, 1911-12, undated (Box 38, Folder 632)
      - World War I, 1916-17 (Box 39, Folder 633-634)
      - World War I, albums, 1916-17 (Box 39, Folder 635)
  - Lewis and Emily (Nash) Bodman, undated (Box 39, Folder 636)
  - Luther Bodman, Jr. family, circa 1855, undated (Box 39, Folder 637)
  - Robert Edgar Bodman, undated (Box 39, Folder 638)
  - Miscellaneous Bodmans, 1899-1975, undated (Box 39, Folder 639)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 39, Folder 640)
  - Bodman gravestones, 1976, undated (Box 39, Folder 641)
  - Bodman houses, 1880-1975, undated (Box 39, Folder 642)
  - Helen Hills Hills Chapel, Smith College, undated (Box 39, Folder 643)
  - Martha Warner chest, c. 1979 (Box 39, Folder 644)
- NEGATIVES
  - Theodora (Dunham) Bodman
    - World War I ambulance corps (Box 40, Folder 1-7)
    - Children (Box 40, Folder 8-19)
  - Henry Taylor Bodman (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Herbert Luther Bodman, Jr., 1943 (Box 41, Folder 21-23)
  - Violet Bodman
    - At Hill House with dogs (Box 41, Folder 24-27)
    - Wedding (Box 41, Folder 28-35)
  - Photos used in A Bodman Chronicle (Box 41, Folder 36-43)
  - Unidentified (Box 41, Folder 44-45)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - GENERATION I
    - Joseph Bodman
      - Deed: Josiah and Hepzibah Dewey to Joseph Bodman 1697 (Box 42, Folder 645)
      - Deed: Martin Kellogg to Joseph Bodman January 30, 1707 (Box 42, Folder 645)
  - GENERATION II
    - Manoah Bodman: deed - Ebenezer Billing to Manoah Bodman, 19 Jun 1728 (Box 42, Folder 646)
    - Samuel Bodman: deed - Joseph Morton to Samuel Bodman, 27 Jun 1717 (Box 42, Folder 647)
    - Samuel and William Bodman
      - Deed - Jonathan and Nathaniel Smith to Samuel and William Bodman, 8 Mar 1717 (Box 42, Folder 648)
      - Deed - Ebenezer Billing to Samuel and William Bodman, 10 Jun 1720 (Box 42, Folder 648)
  - GENERATION III
    - Joseph Bodman
      - Accounts, 1776-79 (Box 42, Folder 649)
      - Deed - Nathan Stark to Abner and Gros Williams, 3 Sep 1803 (Box 42, Folder 649)
    - Samuel Bodman
      - Note of debt - Eliphalet and John Bulkley to Samuel Bodman, 3 Apr 1774 (Box 42, Folder 650)
      - Probate list - Estate of Jesse Wild, expenses and legacies, 29 Sep 1807 (Box 42, Folder 650)
  - GENERATION IV
    - Joseph Bodman
      - Deed - Alfred and Sylvester Bodman to John Wells and Joseph Bodman, 1 Sep 1818 (Box 42, Folder 651)
      - Deed - Stephen Hopkins to Joseph Bodman, 21 Jan 1837 (Box 42, Folder 651)
    - Luther Bodman, Sr.: bill of sale for chattels - Erastus B. Hillman to Luther Bodman, 30 Oct 1830 (Box 42, Folder 652)
  - GENERATION V
    - Lewis Bodman: certificate of governor's appointment as justice of the peace, 4 Mar 1873 (Box 42, Folder 653)
    - Luther Bodman, Jr.
      - List of stock on hand, 4 Jun 1853 (Box 42, Folder 654)
      - Passport, 1879 (Box 42, Folder 654)
  - GENERATION VI
    - Clara Philena Bodman
      - Passport, 28 Feb 1899 (Box 42, Folder 655)
      - D.A.R. membership paper, 7 Dec 1898 (Box 42, Folder 655)
    - Edward Cushman and Ida (Berdan) Bodman: marriage license, 8 Jan 1878 (Box 42, Folder 656)
    - Lewis Henry Bodman: certificate of honorable service in the U.S. military, 15 Mar 1887 (Box 42, Folder 657)
  - GENERATION VII
    - Herbert Luther Bodman, Sr.
      - Appointment to second lieutenant, 15 Aug 1917 (Box 42, Folder 658)
      - Appointment to first lieutenant, 31 Dec 1917 (Box 42, Folder 658)
    - Theodora (Dunham) Bodman
      - Ordre de transport, 13 Mar 1917 (Box 42, Folder 659)
      - Passport, 3 Oct 1918 (Box 42)
      - St. Timothy's School: photographs, 1911, undated (Box 43, Folder 660)
      - World War I: album, 1917-18 (Box 43)
      - Scrapbook, 1974-82 (Box 43)
  - GENERATION VIII
    - Robert Edgar Bodman: estate of Edgar Sereno Bodman, auction advertisement, c. 1972 (Box 43, Folder 661)
  - GENERATION IV
    - Joseph Bodman: deed - Augustine W. Fox to John Wells and Joseph Bodman, 19 Jun 1820 (Map-case Flat file)
  - GENERATION VII
    - Theodora (Dunham) Bodman: posters advertising speeches re relief work, c. 1917 (Map-case Flat file)